Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Los Angeles, Electric Automobile Co. Certificate of articles of incorporation of file. 1908 January 25 1 l., printed form filled in and signed, 48 x 52 cm. (Box 20)
    Signed by C. F. Curry, Secretary of State of California, with Seal.
  - Los Angeles County, California. Assessment list, County of Los Angeles. 1878 2 pages. Printed form filled in. (Box 8)
  - Los Angeles Music Center. Invitation., 1962. (Box 197, Folder 6)
    Dedication of Los Angeles Music Center, October 1962.
    Gift of Franklin D. Murphy.
  - Lossing, Brian J. Letter to John A. McAllister., 1875 23 September.; (1 item, 2pp. [holograph]). (Box 282, Folder 13)
    re vacation news and requesting future visit by McAllister.
  - Louis XIV, King of France, 1638-1715. Correspondence to the Marquis de Poyonne. Sedan. 1657 August 10 2 p. 35.5x 24.5 cm. Manuscript with holograph signature. (Box 23)
    Scope and Content
    Oversize. This letter discusses the French seige of Montmedy (then part of Luxembourg) and the subsequent French victory. With typescript translation.
  - Louisiana. Deed., 1799. (Box 197, Folder 5)
    Deed in Spanish of land sale east of Province of Louisiana.
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891. At the commencement dinner, 1866. In acknowledging a toast to the Smith professor. [Cambridge, Massachusetts]. 1866 4 leaves. 25 by 19.5 centimeters. Holograph. (Box 12)
    A poem written for a Harvard commencement dinner, 1866; in "Complete Poetical Works," 1902. With this: a holograph letter from Oliver Wendell Holmes to the printer making arrangements for the printing of the poem; and a galley proof of the printed poem. 1 leaf.
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891. Correspondence regarding Harvard University. Cambridge, Massachusetts. 1864,1876 2 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    Includes correspondence written 1864 December 19 to Thomas Hill, president of Harvard. Also includes correspondence written 1876 March 2 to A. Denham & Co., regarding a copy of Homer to be given to Harvard.
  - Lowndes, Charles. To John Nicholson, Georgetown, MD. 1796 Oct 2 Holograph signed. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Lowndes, William Thomas, 1798 ? -1843. Holograph letter, 1 page. no date (Box 9)
    In folder, together with two holograph letters by Simon Nowell-Smith to Muirhead on purchase of Lowndes volumes.
  - Luck, Amos. To President [Abraham] Lincoln, Washington. 1861 June 20 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the appointment of a federal marshall. Luck conveys the recommendation by Governor [Salmon P.] Chase of Ohio of a Mr. French as the best choice for the office.
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1906-1982. Sweet are the uses of usage. Book review of Modern English usage by H. W. Fowler. New York. 1958 136-154 p. 15 leaves. 29 cm. Extensive holograph corrections and revisions in pencil. (Box 30)
    Gift of Philip Durham, 1960 June.
    Text extracted from the 1958 May 17 issue of The New Yorker. Mr. Macdonald has taken two copies of his article, revised and corrected it for inclusion in Harbrace College Reader, edited by Mark Schorer, Philip Durham, and Everett L. Jones, Harcourt, Brace & Co., New York, 1959. With this: letter from Dwight Macdonald to Philip Durham discussing the manuscript. New York, 1958 September 15. 1 p.
  - Mackay, Charles, 1814-1889. Signed correspondence. V.p., v.d. ca. 1824-1880 39 items. Holograph (Box 5)
    Letter of 1853 Feb 16 is to Charles John Kean, the actor. Letter to Henry Vizetelly, undated. 1 letter to William Bernard MacCabe, 1857 Feb 24. 1 letter to E. F. Rimbault, 1851 March 1. 1 letter to M. F. Tupper, 1867 June 26. 3 Letters to Thomas Purnell, 1878 and 1880. 1 Letter to John Britton, 1849 Oct. 26. 1 letter to Archibald Constable, 1824 May 17. 1 Letter to William Jerdan, 1851 Oct. 11. 1 letter to Charles John Plumptre, 1860 April 20.
  - Mackay, Charles, 1814-1889. Literary manuscripts. v.p., v.d. 1857-1885 4 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Contents - Returning messengers. New York, Dec. 6, 1857. 1 leaf - The bard's recompense:- dead. n.p., n.d. 1 leaf - Music hall literature. n.p., ca. 1878. 9 leaves - Lost reverence. London, July 11, 1885.
  - MacDonald, J. Fred. Material re Japanese-American recordings., 1982.; (11 items, 8pp. and 9 audio tapes [cassette] in 3 reel-reel boxes). (Box 281, Folder 6)
    Letter to Che-Hwei Lin (UCLA), and index [of tape contents].
  - Macfall, Haldane, 1860-1928. Letters, signed, to Holbrook Jackson. London. 1911-1918. 16 items. holograph manuscripts. (Box 4)
    These letters cover a variety of subjects.
  - Mackenzie, Compton, Sir, 1883-1972. Carnival. Holograph manuscript in pencil for chapters 21-25 of Carnival. Circa 1912 68 pages. 32 cm. In folder. (Box 32)
    Published by Secker, 1912. Approximately 23,000 words.
  - MacIntyre, Carlyle Ferren, 1890-1967. Correspondence and papers., 1937-1957.; (23 items, 23pp.). (Box 287, Folder 4)
    8 letters (5 from CM), 1 telegram. 2 poems (1 dated 14 December 1937 from "Kay"). Miscellaneous bills & receipts.
    Card under MacIntyre, Carlyle--correspondence & papers.
  - Maclaren-Ross, Julain, d. 1946. [Funny bone, 1956] (Box 6)
    Purchase: Rota 1956.
    Approximately 160 pages in 2 folders consisting of typescript, holograph pages, clippings of first magazine appearances and galley proofs. Published: Funny bone, Elek books limited, London 1956.
  - Madville, G. W. Correspondence. 1858 September 1 (Box 8)
    Gift of Henry Clifford, 1953 August 1.
    Written as United States Surveyor General for California appointing Hays as his deputy for the final survey of the Rancho Trabuco. Includes copy of diseo for Rancho Trabuco, 1 leaf. Photostat. 2 leaves. L.S. (Photostat)
  - Magee, John. Riding the Wind. (Box 5)
    Typescript of poem (autograph: Basil Rathbone?). Short biographical sketch of John Magee.
  - Magidson, Herbert, 1906-1986. The continental. Lyrics by Herb Magidson. Music by Con Conrad. Los Angeles. 1934 8 p. 34.5 x 27 cm. Holograph. (Box 23)
    Gift of Herbert Magidson, March, 1950.
    Oversize. Written for "The Gay Divorcee," RKO Radio picture, 1934. This song won an Oscar Award.
  - Madison, James, 1751-1836. "To William A. Coffee, under cover to Joseph Monlyneux," Montpellier, Virginia. 1823 September 12 1 p. Note initialed. (Box 31)
    Madison acknowledges receipt of a copy of Inside Out, a study of abuses in New York state prisons, and hopes that author Coffee's talents would verify his sentiments, and enable him to provide for his family.
  - Mainwaring, Roland. 1 als. 1889 Dec 21 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Mainwaring, Rowland. Annal of bath, from the year 1800 to the passing of the municipal act. *DA 690 B3M2
  - Mallarmé, Stéphane, 1842-1898. Postcard, signed, to Revue Blanche. Paris. 1895 March 20 1 p., holograph. (Box 27)
    Mallarmé promises to deliver an article in person.
  - Mallock, William Hurrell, 1849-1923. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 24 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    1 letter to Sir James Thomas Knowles, 1904 December 9.
  - Marcellino, Eugenio. Composition for band. Turin. 1895 January 18 33 unnumbered pages. Holograph manuscript (music). (Box 23)
    Gift of William Grant Still, 1958 January 23.
    Oversize. With this: Diploma issued by L'Accademia de Quiriti to Eugenio Marcellino, 1863 January 23.
  - Marquis, Neeta. Correspondence and booklets. (Box 4)
    Gift of Miss Marquis via Lindley Bynum, together with some small books of poetry and little magazines.
  - Marquis, Neeta. The Land Grant of the Rubois: A Novel - Manuscript., (1 item, 150pp. [typescript carbon] - 2 copies). (Box 287, Folder 6)
    In holograph at top: third carbon - 8 chapters only.
    Purchase: Arundel.
  - Marr, Janey Hope. To General John G. Roller, Norfolk, Virginia. 1897 July 7 4 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Mrs. Marr refers to new buildings at her husband's institute, and to her own short stories.
  - Marryat, Frederick, 1792-1848 (Box 284, Box 285)
    - Manuscript., n.d.; (1 item, 2pp. [holograph]). (Box 285, Folder 11)
      A Page from the Author's Snarleyyow.
      Purchase: Wilder Books.
    - Letter and etching of author., c. 1829.; (1 item, 2pp. [holograph]). (Box 284, Folder 3)
      Letter to publisher of his book Naval Officer.
      Purchase: James Burmeister.
  - Marshall, O. H. To Messrs. Gales and Seaton, Buffalo. 1835 November 30 1 l. A.L.S. (Box 10)
    With the above: Love, Thomas C[utting] To Messrs. Gales and Seaton [Washington] 1835 December 8. A.N.S.
  - Marston, John Westland, 1819-1890. Correspondence. Circa 1849-1865 14 items. Holograph. (Box 27)
    1 letter to George Henry Lewes, 1849 July 28. 1 letter to James Hain Friswell, 1865 June 12.
  - Mason, Jeremiah, 1768-1848. To Albert Gallatin, Georgetown [D.C.]. 1812 August 7 2 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Mason, Senator from New Hampshire, writes to the Secretary of the Treasury, recommending Thomas Baker for clerk in the department.
  - Mata Hari, 1876-1917. Jugement rendu par le 3 Conseil de Guerre.., (1 item, 4pp. [in French]). (Box 282, Folder 9)
    Certified copy of the trial and judgement against Mata Hari for spying.
  - Mathais, Mable. Letter from Marion County, Iowa Public Schools., 1918. (Box 201, Folder 1)
    Includes teaching certificate.
  - Mathews, Anne (Jackson), 1782?-1869. Correspondence to Horace Mayhew. 1862 March-July 4 items. Holograph. 4 letters. (Box 19)
  - Matthews, Stanley, 1824-1889. Correspondence. 2 pieces in 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Maugham, William Somerset, 1874-1965. Correspondence. V.p., v.d. 1923-1927, 1943 10 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 5)
    6 letters to Charles Hanson Towne, 1923-1925. 3 letters to Miss Morse, 1926-1927. 1 letter to Lawrence Clark Powell, 1943 Jan 19.
  - Holy Roman Empire. Sovereigns, etc., 1564-1576 (Maximilian II). Document, signed by Maximilian II. Vienna. 1570 November 8 3 p. 31 x 21.5 cm. Manuscript with holograph signature. (Box 30)
    Maximilian writes to the Mayor and the Council of Wumpfen (?) that he has dispatched "Sebaldus von Plarun to deal with you in matters concerning Us." He goes on to "recommend that you not only believe him in all things, but that you also act obediently afterwards." With transcript.
  - Maunder, Samuel, 1785-1849. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Mazzini, Guiseppi, 1805-1872. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Mc Laen, Thomas (?). To Jasper Yeates, Philadelphia. 1795 Aug 8 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
    Concerning financial investments of Yeates, who was Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania.
  - McCauley, John F., et al. Correspondence. (Box 8)
    To J[ohn] Neely Johnson. 3 letters. Request for the pardon of Hiram Durham and statement as to his health.
  - McCoppin, Frank. Correspondence. 1868 May 16 3 pages. A.L.S. (Box 8)
    To H[enry] H[untley] Haight, San Francisco, May 16, 1868. Recommending the appointment of a notary public for the city of San Francisco.
  - Maynard, Theodore. Correspondence. 1927, 1928, 1932, 1934 (Box 5)
    2 tls 1932, 1934. 2 als 1927, 1928.
  - Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth (Braddon), 1837-1915. His good fairy. undated 10 leaves. Holograph. (Box 32)
    A short story. Publishing history unknown.
  - Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth (Braddon), 1837-1915. Correspondence, signed. 12 items. Holograph. (Box 32)
  - Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth (Braddon), 1837-1915. "My best story and why I think so." "His oldest friends." London, The Grand Magazine. 1905 7 l. 56 x 17 cm. Galleys with holograph corrections. (Box 32)
    The first leaf is stamped, "The Grand Magazine. 6 Jun. 1905. Editorial Department." With this: Memorandum to the Editor of The Grand Magazine, 1905 May 30. Author's note to: "His Oldest Friends, by Miss Braddon." This manuscript statement is in the hand of W. H. S. Maxwell.
  - Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth (Braddon), 1837-1915. Three Times Dead-related materials. 1887-1942 8 pieces in one folder. (Box 32)
    Removed from Sadleir Number 335.
    Holograph letter from Maxwell, dated 1896 March 31, written from Annesley Bank, Lyndhurst, Hants, to Mr. James Mills, at Beverley, Yorks, concerning proof sheets of Three Times Dead. Holograph letters signed from John Maxwell, publisher, dated 1887 April 19, written from St. James's Magazine, to Charles Empson, publisher, concerning publication rights to Three Times Dead. Holograph letter signed from Charles R. Empson, dated 1896 January 2, written from Hull, to Mr. James Mills of Beverley, asking for help at a time of bereavement. Loose pages from published edition of Three Times Dead: pages 25-32 (from chapters VII and VIII) and pages 57, 58, 63, and 64 (from Chapters I and II). Also includes, 3 clippings and a 1 page holograph discussion of the bibliographical history of this novel.
  - McWilliams, Carey, 1905-. Letters and Trouble at Sequoia [Manuscript]., 1949-1950.; (4 items, 26pp. [typescript carbon] and [holograph & typescript]). (Box 282, Folder 22)
    Also, 3 letters to McWilliams, one re censorship.
    Card under McWilliams.
  - Medici, Marie de. Expenditures., 1631.; (12 vellum leaves). (Box 193, Folder 1)
    Recording daily expenditures of Marie de Medici for September 8-28, 1631.
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Melanchthon, Philipp, 1497-1560. Correspondence. Germany. undated 2 items. Holograph. (Box 30)
    Ex libris: Isaac Foot.
    1 letter in Latin to his servant John, Torgau, August 15 (no year). 1 leaf. 1 letter in Latin to "Reverend" (a priest?), undated. 1 leaf.
  - Menken, Adah Isaacs, 1835-1868. Research material re life of Menken., (Approximately 200pp.). (Box 282, Folder 1)
    Actress and poet. Includes information on Angelica Kaufman. Compiler unknown.
    From Gifts and Endowments.
  - Meredith, William Morris, 1799-1873. To D.L. Hurgeon, Philadelphia. 1838 September 20 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Meridith, William Morris, 1799-1873. To Joseph Watson. 1827 April 21. Holograph signed. 2 p. (Box 4)
    Meridith, then President of the Select Council of Philadelphia, to Watson, then Mayor of that city, recommending Henry M. Read, son of John Read, as Vaccine Physician for the city.
  - Merrell, Benjamin. Correspondence. 1802 July 16 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 8)
    To [Rueben Merrell?], Charleston [?].
  - Mexican Labor Movement. A collection of 44 documents: Mexico City, 26 September to 14 December, 1941., n.d.; (Typescript [in Spanish]). (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Mill, John Stuart, 1806-1873. Correspondence. V.p., v.d. 1868-1869 3 items. Holograph.
    1 letter to Hewett Cottrell Watson, 1969 Jan 30. 1 Letter to Lord Vere Henrey Hobart, 1868 Feb 23.
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950. 4 poems. To a lady in a position of influence, To S. M., telegram to T. H., the burning bridge. typescript, 2 p. (Box 20)
    Gift: Joe Swerling.
    At the back of page: "This is the original manuscript of the poem 'To S. M.' submitted by E. St. V. Millay for use in a Few Figs from Thistles. (signed) Frank Shay."
  - Miller, Henry, 1891- (Box 284, 287-289)
    - Postcards & letters to Gilbert's Book Shop and Satyr Book Shop., (20 items, 11pp. [holograph, 1 typescript]). (Box 284, Folder 6)
      Ephemera.
      re book orders and payments.
      Part of Nin and Miller archive from Gilbert's and the Satyr shops.
    - Ephemera (3 items) and list of addresses [holograph]., 1957-1960.; (8 items, 5pp.). (Box 287, Folder 3)
      Includes envelope to Mrs. Arthur Knight, dated 5 April (no year).
      Purchase: Jeff Weber. Card under Miller, Henry--ephemera.
    - Letters and postcards to Vearl Moody., 1978-1979.; (73 items, 60pp.). (Box 287, Folder 8)
      55 letters [holograph] with 29 envelopes, and 18 postcards [holograph].
      Purchase: Jeff Weber.
      Card under Miller, Henry--correspondence.
    - Henry Miller 84: A Video Portrait (no.1-2), by John Hunt., n.d.; (2 video cassette [VHS], 18 minutes each). (Box 288, Folder 2)
      Card under Miller, Henry.
    - Interview transcript., 1975-1976.; (5 items, 52pp. [typescript photocopy] - 2 copies). (Box 289, Folder 1)
      Interview by John Hunt, December 1975-May 1976.
      1 copy in four sections.
    - Letters and photographs., 1971-1972.; (8 items, 8pp.). (Box 289, Folder 7)
      6 letters from Miller to Mr. Evans and Mr. Firestone.
      Purchase: Transition Card under H.Miller.
  - Miller, Joaquin, 1837-1913. Papers. (Box 20)
    Letter to Dr. Conway, 1873 March 1. Letter to Herman Whitaker, June 18. Letter to Mr. McLaughlin, 1893 March 7. Printed poems entitled "The Dead Millionaire," and "The Fortunate Isles" with corrections by the author in his own handwriting. Photocopy of letter to William Hayes Ward, 1873 January 3. Photocopy of poem on the death of Bret Harte by Miller, 1902.
  - Mills, Barries. 2 letters to Ronald Voigt., 1979-1981.; (2 items, 6pp. [holograph]). (Box 285, Folder 14)
    re poerty, music, miscellaneous topics.
    Found in Mill's Roughened Roundness (New York: 1976).
  - Mills, Darius Ogden, 1825-1910. To Mister Leech, New York. March 5 2 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Mills, New York and San Francisco banker, writes to obtain the services of musician Leech for a dinner concert.
  - Mills, Enos A. 4 letters to William E. Colby., 1909-1913.; (4 items, 6pp. [3 holograph, 1 typed]). (Box 283, Folder 5)
    re founding of Rocky Mountain (Estes) National Park (Colorado) and Hetch-Hetchy Park (California).
  - Mitford, Mary Russell, 1787-1955. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. Circa 1825-1854 18 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    1 letter to John Ruskin, 1852 October 1. Included is a holograph fragment from "Rienzi," 1841 March 7. 1 letter to Archdeacon Francis Wrangham, 1825 March 9. 1 letter to William Cox Bennett, 1854 August 23. 1 letter to Samuel Carter Hall, 1834 October 24.
  - Molesworth, Mary Louise (Stewart) 1842-1921. Correspondence. 3 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Montgomery, G.V. (U.S. Representative--California). Veteran's Administration land sale., 1986. (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - Mooney, Thomas J. Petition of Thomas J. Mooney for a pardon presented to Governor Frank F. Merriam., n.d.; (Typescript, bound). (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - Moore, Charles, H. 1 als. 1890 Apr 5 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Moore, Charles H., Gothic architecture.
  - Moore, George, 1852-1933. Correspondence. Circa 1911-1931 14 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 29)
    3 letters to Mr. Bourgeois, 1911 July. 2 letters to Edward Fordham Spence, 1915 and 1916. 1 letter to Percy Atkin, 1931 November 24. With this: a letter to O. Atkin from F. H. Swift of Spurr and Swift, booksellers, 1924 September 20. Swift discusses the price of some George Moore books. 1 letter to Gustav Holst, [circa 1930] October 3.
  - Moore, T. Sturge (Box 284, Folder 1-2)
    - 10 letters and poem., 1925-1939.; (11 items, 18pp.). (Box 284, Folder 1)
      Poem: "Footfalls" [holograph], 16 lines (n.d.).
      Gift of the Charles B. Gullans Estate.
    - Tyrfing - Manuscript playscript [unpublished?]., n.d.; (1 item, 34pp. [typescript]). (Box 284, Folder 2)
      Typescript with holograph corrections and annotations, with original cover.
      Gift of Charles B. Gullans Estate.
  - Morgan, Sydney (Owenson), Lady, 1783?-1859. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 53 items. Holograph. (Box 30)
    3 letters to Anna Maria Hall, undated and 1855. 1 letter to William Charles Macready, undated. 1 letter to Captain Frederick Marryat, 1833 May 15. 1 letter to Lady Catherine Stepney, undated.
  - Morier, James Justinian, 1780?-1849. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. Circa 1818, 1832 9 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    Letter to "My dear Sir," 1832 November 14, refers to Sir Walter Scott. Letter to John Murray, 1818 January 18.
  - Morley, George. Letter to Ernest P. Webb, Esq., (of the Sunday Chronicle)., 1901 5 March.; (1 item, 1p. [holograph]). (Box 281, Folder 7)
    Found in Morley's In Rustic Livery (1896).
  - Morley, John Morley, viscount, 1839-1923. Correspondence. 5 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Morris, Sir Lewis, 1833-1907. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
  - Morrow, William Chambers, 1853-1923. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 25)
    Taken from PS 659 S75S Spinners' Book of Fiction.
  - Muir, John, 1838-1914. The Yosemite valley. 1911 July Circa 600 leaves. Typescript (carbon) and holograph. (Box 33)
    Purchase: Scribner's bookstore, 1946.
    Includes carbon copy of The Yosemite by John Muir (New York, Century Co., 1912), various stages of writing of several chapters, some plates from the book, and a typescript of "The Kings river Yosemite" which did not appear in the book.
  - Mundy, Talbot, 1879-1940. Correspondence. 3 items. Typescript, signed. (Box 17)
  - Munroe, Kirk, 1850-1930. Correspondence, Miami, Florida. November 14? 1 p. Holograph. (Box 20)
    On stationary of Biscayne Bay Yacht Club.
  - Murman, Eugene Otto Walter, 1874-1962. Autobiographical sketch, Canoga Park, Calif. 1954 Oct 27 5 l. typescript. (Box 5)
    Gift of Eugene O. W. Murman, 1954.
  - Murman, Eugene Otto Walter, 1874-1962. Autobiographical sketch, Canoga Park, Calif. 1942 Apr 27 7 l. typescript signed. (Box 5)
    Eugene O. W. Murman, 1942.
  - Murphy, Arthur. Letter to Jim Brown., 1943 20 October.; (1 item, 1p.). (Box 282, Folder 3)
    re remarks on Murphy's First Harvest (1943).
    Found in Murphy's First Harvest.
  - Murray, Sir Charles Augustus, 1806-1895. Correspondence. Circa 1844 2 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
    1 letters to Patrick Fraser Tytler, 1844 November 19.
  - Native Daughters of the Golden West. California Parlor Number 247. Correspondence. 1951 January 10 1 leaf. T.L.S. (Box 8)
    To [Lindley Bynum] Los Angeles. Invitation to the presentation of the official photograph of Miss Mary Emily Foy to the Los Angeles Public LIbrary.
  - Needell, Mary Anna. 1 als. 1889 Aug 20 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Needell, Mary Anna. Stephen Ellicottt's daughter, v.1.
  - Nethersole, Olga. Correspondence. 1908 June 1 1 leaf. T.S. (Box 8)
    To James N[orris] Gillette, New York. An appeal in behalf of Percy Pembroke.
  - Newenham, Sir Edward, 1732-1814. Correspondence. 1779-1789 38 letters (photocopy). (Box 33)
    Purchased on research grant of Dixon Wecter.
    Letters chiefly to Benjamin Franklin concerning support of American Independence in Ireland and England. Newenham was M. P. for Dublin, 1776-1797, and Baron of the Exchequer in Ireland. Originals in American Philosophical Society and the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - Purchased on research grant of Dixon Wector. (Box 33)
    Original in the Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley.
    Letters concerning Newenham's support of the cause of American Independence and reception of same by Congress. Janssens, Victor Eugene August. Vida y adventuras en CaliforniaSanta Barbara, California. 1878 March 30 223 numbered pages. Photostat. Pages 1-8 missing.
  - Newhall (H. M.) & Co., auctioneers, San Francisco. 1 leaf. (Box 7)
    [Broadside of opium and rice auction, Oct. 12, 1875, corner of Sansome and Halleck Sts., San Francisco].
  - Newsweek Educational Bureau. Sound Motion Picture. 1946. (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Nhan, Nguyen Hoai. Vietnam: its future., 1981.; (Holograph, photocopy?). (Box 196, Folder 2)
  - Nicholas, Philip Nosborne, 1773-1849. To Joseph Watson, Richmond. 1826 Dec 8 Holograph signed. 2p. (Box 4)
    Nicholas, President of Farmers bank of VA., acknowledges service of the police under Watson, Mayor of Philadelphia, and a couple who detected counterfeiters.
  - Nichols, Beverley. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 15)
  - Nichols, Robert Malise Bowyer, 1893-1944. Correspondence to Robert Nichols. 1916, 1918 3 items. Manuscript. (Box 19)
    1 letter from Walter De La Mare, 1916 October 30. 1 letter from John Galsworthy, 1918 September 6. 1 letter from Edmund Gosse, 1918 August 8.